Elier Hernandez

Full-Stack Software Developer



elierporto@gmail.com





786-478-5402 <u>elierhernandez.com</u>



in <u>LinkedIn</u>



@ElierHP

Projects

Pencils and Inks

Pencils and Inks is an e-commerce website that was developed from scratch using React & Next js for the client side and Ruby on Rails for the server API. The website includes various features such as; products, users, filter settings, a review system with ratings, a shopping cart, and an admin panel for CRUD operations.

Webmarks

Webmarks is an online file system that allows users to store folders and urls on the web. The front end for this application was built using React and Material UI. The back end API was built using Node with Express, and the user authentication was handled with Passport.

Skyline Media Marketing

Skyline is an advertisement agency located in New York. I worked with them on various projects for multiple clients, including their own main website. The website was designed in Figma, and built using React and Gatsby. After the creation of the website, the client experienced a 100%+ increase in leads from their marketing campaigns. It was a huge success.

Work Experience

Developer & Designer @ Skyline Management, Inc.

2019 – 2022 // Miami, FL

- ▶ Build client websites using Wordpress, React and Gatsby.
- ▶ Help agency clients build a strong online web presence.
- Design graphics to increase Facebook Marketing conversions.
- Design new branding material for the company that included the logo, business cards, and branded uniform for employees.

Game Designer @ Spire Studios

2016 – 2018 // Miami, FL

- Design the user Interface and experience for the application.
- Design pixel graphics and illustrations for the project.
- ▶ Work with a team to create and implement visual assets into the game.

Operations Manager @ Retail Paradigm

2015 – 2016 // Miami, FL

- Perform various operational tasks
- ▶ Keyword research and optimization
- Managed inventory and supplies

Skills

Programming Languages

HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, Ruby

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, Gatsby, Styled Components, Emotion.js, Express, Material UI

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Webpack, Netlify, Heroku

Design

Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator

Education

Miami Dade College

2014 – 2016 // Miami, FL

Pursued bachelors of arts.

Languages

English – Spanish

Interests

development, design, drawing & painting, video games, reading, table tennis, philosophy, business, investing.